[Music]
[Applause]
hello everyone and welcome to another
episode of is it worth it and this month
we're going to be doing something a
little bit special we are going to
follow one product without one product
one type of product through the entire
month and thus we are going to embark on
March marker madness so so the entire
month we're gonna do nothing but markers
okay and I really want to try and get a
nice gamut of different kind of markers
so this is gonna be the first one and
I'm really excited about this one
because I found these in Walmart okay I
bought this 12-pack for $10 I went
around and I started looking on Amazon
and stuff like that and they go for like
17 dollars so I must have caught it on
sale at Walmart but I did find these at
Walmart okay so it's 12 markers for 10
bucks and even twelve dollars for 17
bucks if they're any good they're gonna
be I mean that guess they're gonna be
pretty good for the price but we're
gonna test it out and we are going to
see whether or not if you're in a bind
if you can use these if they're even
worth it okay so I hope that you will
join us to find out whether or not the
Azure markers from Walmart or Amazon are
actually worth getting as a hobby artist
or professional so let's dive on into
this sketchbook and let's see how they
work all right so here we go so we are
getting back into the Crescent art
marker paper sketchbook we're gonna go
ahead and use that for all the markers
that we're gonna use and let's go ahead
and crack these open
[Music]
okay so first off I like the fact that
they come in this nice plastic case
right keeps them all together that's
nice nice clean look let's take them out
okay so it is in a triangular shape
they're rounded at the edges they're
nice and vibrant as far as seeing the
color I don't know if those would rub
off or not but they they seem to fit
really nice in your hand you know by the
triangle spot there's always a flat
surface for you to grab onto and a place
a butcher your fingers for control so
that's good okay it's already got a blue
line around it though no know if you
guys can sorry I don't know if you guys
can see that
nope okay but the the thick parts
already framed that's not bad
see if there's another one that's trust
look at the screen nope okay it's maybe
was just the blue one where the market
was a bit beat up and there's no green
on this one so check out this purple so
from what I'm seeing these colors are
like super vibrant right like these this
is the primary set so I did get a
primary set but they seem to be very
very vibrant the colors might be a bit
too strong I noticed that they do have a
couple others they have skin tones they
have muted colors so we'll see what
happens and then we also have a blender
just in case you are a blending type
person okay love the snap right like you
can really hear it snapping so you know
when it's closed right so that's nice I
love that future so many times I'll have
markers that just you think they're
closed but they're never really closed
go ahead and jump right into these
markers alright so we're gonna try some
of the more saturated colors and see
what happens
[Music]
okay it's pretty cool all right goes
down fairly easy okay it's nice nice
even tone seems to be working pretty
nice let's try a different red the
darker red that they gave us
[Music]
all right these look good and they're
they're definitely flowing real nice so
just keep then we're gonna take a closer
look at it to see how it's bleeding or
what not if it's bleeding so the the
actual nips and stuff are very strong on
these they don't bend they're not
bending and doing weird things when you
use them so that's really nice
they do seem to blend with themselves
you know so you don't have to don't
really have to worry about it being all
streaky and stuff that's good and it
doesn't take a lot of ink to cover the
surface to make sure that it's nice and
covered let's see this purple so like I
said the colors are super vibrant so
they go on like you don't need a lot of
color to make this happen
so it's like I've marked on it so the
lighter colors need a little bit more
love
all right so you gonna have to go over
it a couple more times but look at that
I mean those are nice hey what's up
y'all little closer in there so for the
most part I really don't see a lot of
bleeding that's happening so if you have
a lot of if you have some ink lines
alright if you have a drawing where you
inked it up that should be nice hmm and
it'll it doesn't really bleed much and
it really only seems as though when it's
in the real darker now that's on the
edges so we've got a little bit here on
the edges but like I said if you're
actually using a a line drawing and you
have an ink line that's gonna bud right
up against that ink line and that'll be
really nice but these colors are super
vibrant right they these are the primary
colors so they're they're really nice so
they gave us a blending stick so let's
go ahead and we're gonna try and blend
these three colors and see what happens
okay
all right okay blue darker blue
and that's purple
hmm now I'm gonna break out this
blending blending marker let's see what
happens there
you
it seems to be working between the blue
and the purple but not so much this this
one II I don't know if the I don't
really know if that blending stick is
something except let's try it again go
ahead and clean that off real quick
let's try and get it while it's wet all
right so we're gonna do this blue this
blue while it's hopefully still wet
blending stump
[Music]
all right I mean you can see kind of
works it is kind of blending out you can
do it
so what I'm seeing though is that the
blending the actual blending utensil has
to pick up a whole bunch of the marker
color first before you can actually
blend it out because it's gonna pull all
that color on there right and then you
can constantly go in and work it
I mean so you can go in and work it to
make it blend but all I did right heat
lips that's really wet um but right here
you know it's got a very strong division
between the light and the dark and it
was very fresh you know so I don't know
why it's doing that
let's try it let's try a different color
get all this blue off for you
try it let's try and blend these this
green
the screen and I'm assuming that you
should do it while it's wet because if
it dries up how are you gonna blend it
right so we're gonna come in here see
the issue that I'm having with this
blending tool is the fact that it when
it takes the color it doesn't get rid of
this like these lines so you're always
getting this weird division going on and
it's like completely coverage yeah so I
don't I don't think the blends like it's
really cool after the fact like when you
pick up color that might be interesting
right where you could pick up color and
then make it kind of look like this fade
it out wash look so I think that's
pretty cool let's see maybe if we just
do one color
alright let me just pause
because it does pull the color out
when maybe maybe now go over it
[Music]
I mean it like I said you can you can
make it blend right so it does blend but
it looks as though you need like a
little space and then you can blend it
out right like you you put a little
overlap and then you blend them together
you can't really lace them on top with
and getting a nice seamless edge but it
does look really cool like with this so
if you actually use the blending stump
and then go all right I've used it and I
pulled Green out right you can then come
in and pull some of that green and let
it kind of watercolor itself out so
that's the nice little effect I don't
know if that was intentional but it's
it's a nice little effect so so far you
know I'm like all right I like this for
me this really works the blending things
not exactly working from what I can tell
it like I said it does blend right like
you can see it here alright there are
some transitions but it seems as though
when the marker hits it just pulls and
it doesn't necessarily always just make
it seamless go see this but you know
there you go so I'm going to gonna do a
little drawing and I'm gonna do my my
style of markering and then we will we
will have our final thoughts all right
let's get to
[Music]
alright so we just got done marking this
up and there are a couple things that I
noticed that are really not sitting with
me so the do marker itself they are too
saturated so these dark colors like
Browns and the purples and stuff they
are way too saturated and so when they
go on it's very very dark and there's
not a lot that you can do with it
I used their light gray that was or
their light brown that was here and when
I put it down in order to make sure that
it was actually sort of even right it
became super dark and my big hope was
that once it dried it was all gonna dry
in one color but apparently there wasn't
enough ink on one side as there was on
the other which is kind of odd because
it was completely covered in marker and
it dried there was lighter here and then
darker here so the effects really cool
all right because it looks as though
there's a light coming from underneath
this character's head but the problem is
so right so it looks like there's light
coming from here the problem is that was
unintentional and so with that said you
know if the marker is not necessarily
controllable and I don't I personally as
a person who uses graphic style and
graphic shapes and stuff like that I
don't necessarily like that very much
because I don't know if it's gonna dry a
certain way and so that's that's a
problem and then it also doesn't like
multiple colors and so it seems that you
have to you really have to let it dry
right so I I did I did this yellow and
then orange and then I did a brown to
try and you know put some volume into
the hair and maybe it was because the
orange was still a little wet I don't
know what I didn't have a lot down so it
shouldn't have taken that long to dry
but it then not only bled so that you
couldn't get a nice fine tip but it also
started pulling up the pigment in the
paper so there are little white dots
everywhere which is also something I
just don't I don't like and it's
normally something with the mixture of
the the ink in the marker that pulls up
the paper or it separates the pores of
the paper so you see those little white
dots and that's something that I just I
just don't like but I mean the main
thing is that it's way too saturated so
the colors are so strong so dark that
you know you have to give everything I
would say perfect on the first shot and
because it is a marker you kind of have
to go over it and blend it to get it
into a nice clean non streak foundation
and in order to you know to do that with
these it gets really really dark and
then you don't exactly know how it dries
so another issue that I was having was
that the bullet point does not allow you
to get a nice fine tip right and I was
having a real hard time just lightly
flicking trying to get
nice strong angle you know a tip for
some of these areas in the hair so
that's that's a problem too so with all
that said the idea of the actual mark I
love the design right it's it's really
nice and you're in your hand that's
really nice I just don't think that this
is actually good for a professional
artist so I think we wouldn't have to
separate this sometimes in the two
separate ideas right so is this worth it
is absorb markers worth it okay I picked
it up at Walmart for $10 and it's on
Amazon for 1675 right so they're not
expensive so is it worth it for a
learning student or someone who's just
doing this as a hobby or doing those
adult coloring books or something like
that
absolutely all right the colors are nice
and vibrant so especially if you're just
literally just trying to get nice
vibrant colors really good for coloring
books you know so I think that that's
really good is it worth it before a more
semi-professional or professional I'd
have to say no no it's not because there
are many issues that are going on with
this that is not allowing you to not
have to worry about what's gonna happen
when you do it so like the blending
right you're having issues with the
blending didn't actually blend out the
way it was supposed to the uneven colors
the inability to actually make the fine
point is all issues that a professional
or semi-professional would not tolerate
and this pack of markers does not live
up to a standard as far as being able to
work professionally without having to
add a whole bunch of other steps and
like I said it's just too dark like this
right here completely obliterated all
the line so you can't even see the line
of the drawing so it's just too dark the
color composition of the markers is just
too saturated too dark so is it worth it
for like a student or hobby artist yes
but the price is great and then you get
a nice vibrant colors is it worth it for
a professional or semi-pro I'd have
they know okay so that is my review of
the sewer base primary the basic set so
the sewer 12-pack basic set that's my
review I hope you enjoyed it I hope that
it was helpful please join us again at
another piece of work video they are
going to come out every single Friday
and this month we were doing all markers
so we're going to be going through
different sets of markers so definitely
join in if you are interested in markers
and as a question to all my viewers
would you prefer that I did more of a
rubric tight style so I can say you know
design color controllability and stuff
like that and actually give it a rating
so that you can actually go off of a
rating or are you okay with just the way
of me way that I've done the videos
before just telling you my thoughts and
then telling you if it's worth it or not
please help me out and drop me a comment
and tell me what you really like but I
really like this series to become
something that it's going to be useful
for the artistic community so please
please please should I use a rubric and
do a grading system or can I still just
keep going the way that I'm going thank
you guys so very much for tuning in and
sticking to sticking with me to the end
and I hope to see you at the next video
thank you very much for watching this
video please like share and subscribe
and if you'd like to check out some of
my other videos click on the link on
your right or if you're interested in a
more behind-the-scenes and personal look
at what I do on a day to day basis
please click on the link that leads you
to the vlog thank you very much and
we'll see you at the next video